(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T18:38:11.025105",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
夢の国を探す君の名を
Searching for the land of dreams, your name
誰もが心に刻むまで
Engraved in everyone's heart until the very end,
悲しみ乗り越えた微笑みに
With a smile that overcame all sadness,
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
終わりがなくて 見つけられなくて 迷ったりしたけれど
With no end in sight, unable to find it, though I sometimes lost my way,
傷ついたこと 失ったもの いつかは輝きに変えて
Every hurt and lost thing will someday turn into brilliance.
後悔に決して負けない翼が きっとあるから
There surely are wings that will never lose to regret.
君とならどこでも 行ける気がする
With you, I feel like I can go anywhere.
夢の国を探す君の名を
Searching for the land of dreams, your name
誰もが心に刻むまで
Engraved in everyone's heart until the very end,
悲しみ乗り越えた微笑みに
With a smile that overcame all sadness,
君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you?
一人ぼっちじゃ 生きてけないって
You can't live all by yourself,
あの時教えてくれた
you taught me that back then.
近くにあっても 気付かずにいた
Even though it was right beside me, I didn't notice it,
本当に大切なこと
the truly precious things.
この空の果てに 何が待っていても きっと大丈夫
No matter what awaits at the end of this sky, I'm sure it'll be alright.
その瞳に映る未来 感じているから
Because I can feel the future reflected in those eyes.
夢の国を探す君の名を 誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone engraves the name of you, who search for the land of dreams, in their hearts,
偶然じゃない運命の中で 君の奇跡を信じてる
amidst a destiny that's no mere coincidence, I believe in your miracle.
夢の楽園を探しながら 走る君を見つめていたい
I want to keep watching you run as you search for the paradise of dreams.
誇り高く汚れを知らない 君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you, so proud and untouched by stain?
夢の国を探す君の名を 誰もが心に刻むまで
Until everyone engraves the name of you, who search for the land of dreams, in their hearts,
悲しみ乗り越えた微笑みに 君を信じていいですか
with a smile that overcame sadness, can I believe in you?
夢の楽園を探しながら 走る君を見つめていたい
I want to keep watching you run as you search for the paradise of dreams.
誇り高く汚れを知らない 君を信じていいですか
Can I believe in you, so proud and untouched by stain?
夢の楽園を探しながら 見つめていたい
As I search for the paradise of dreams, I want to keep watching you,
誇り高く汚れを知らない
so proud and untouched by stain.
はい、ということで！
Alright, with that said!
ホロライブ4期生の不知火フレアです！
I'm Hololive 4th Generation's Shiranui Flare!
今日は遅れて来た私の4周年記念ライブに来てくれて、どうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my slightly delayed 4th anniversary live today!
すみませんね。
Sorry about that.
えー、最初の1曲目を聴いていただきましたが、今回のテーマはなんと！
Um, you've just heard the first song, and this time's theme is...
平成初期アニソン祭り！
Early Heisei Anime Song Festival!
まず、「こういうのがいいんだよ！」って言いたくなっちゃうかもん…なっちゃって
First off, you might feel like saying, "Oh, this is the good stuff!"... or well,
みんなの好きだったあんな曲やこんな曲を歌えたら嬉しいなって思ってます。
I'd be so happy if I could sing all those songs you guys used to love.
ゲストもたくさんいるから楽しみにしててください。
There are lots of guests too, so please look forward to it!
えー、みんなで一緒に楽しんでくれると嬉しいので、ハッシュタグもぜひ活用してください。
Um, I'd be super happy if we could all enjoy this together, so please make use of the hashtag!
ハッシュタグはこちら、「不知火フレア4周年記念ライブ」で、感想と一緒したくさんツイートしてください。
The hashtag is "#ShiranuiFlare4thAnniversaryLIVE". Please tweet lots along with your impressions!
最後に、お知らせもあるから、最後までたくさん楽しんでいってください！
Also, there are announcements at the end, so please enjoy it all the way through!
お？ 早速だけど、どこかでゲストの声がする。
Oh? Right away, I hear a guest's voice somewhere.
どこだろう？
Where could it be?
輝きは君の中に
[Song: Radiance is Within You]
楽しいことでも 毎日続いたら
Even if something is fun, if it continues every day,
それと気付かずに 退屈と変わらないね
you won't even notice and it becomes no different from boredom.
幸せ悲しみ 代わる代わるの波
Happiness and sadness, waves alternating in turn,
心の不思議が 分かりかけてくる
making you begin to understand the mysteries of the heart.
人を愛したら 不安も知るものだけど
When you love someone, you also come to know anxiety,
淋しい心に 深く優しさ染みるよ
but a deep tenderness seeps into a lonely soul.
I can't stop my love for you
2人語った未来に
In the future we both talked about,
君との居場所があるように
May there be a place for me with you.
Oh baby I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね
I want to be everything to you.
2人の目の前 謎めきひろがった 未完成な地図
Before our eyes, an expanding uncompleted map,
でも とても とても とても 心動いた…
But my heart was moved so, so, so much...
どんな言葉 並べてみても 語りきれない想い
No matter what words I arrange, feelings I cannot fully tell,
この愛が ささやくよ 愛しさの意味を
This love whispers the meaning of tenderness.
悲しみを避けて 笑うのは簡単 諦め上手の 大人になりたくない
Avoiding sadness and smiling is easy, but I don't want to give up.
自分ひとりだけ 空回りしてると
When I'm spinning my wheels all by myself,
誰もが器用に 生きてる気がする
It feels like everyone else is living so skillfully.
ひとを傷つけて 自分を守る弱さは 虚しさ残して
The weakness of hurting others to protect oneself leaves emptiness.
やがて自分も傷つく
And eventually hurts oneself too.
2人歩むスピードは きっと同じはずじゃないからね
The speed at which we walk surely won't be the exact same,
もしも君となり この手が離れたときは 見失わないように きっとむかえに来てね
So come welcome me if we lose sight of each other.
「大嫌い」なんて ウソでも言わないけれど
I won't even say "I hate you" as a lie,
「大好き」だって ウソなんかじゃ言わないからね
But I won't say "I love you" as a lie either.
会えない時間(とき)さえ君は 何も考える余裕もないくらい
Even when we can't meet, you take all my heart exclusively,
この心を ひとりじめにするんだから
Leaving me no room to think about anything else.
I can't stop my love for you
2つの愛が 離れてしまわないように 1つに抱いていて
Hold our two loves together so they don't drift apart.
それでも不安な夜は 訪れるものだからね
Even so, uneasy nights are bound to visit us,
そんなときは ぎゅっと 大げさに抱きしめていて
At times like that, hug me tightly and dramatically.
かけがえのないもの 君がたくさんここに来くれた
You gave me so many irreplaceable things here,
だけど 何よりも いちばん
Yet more than anything, the very first,
かけがえのないもの は 君なんだ
The irreplaceable thing is you.
I can't stop my love for you
2人語った未来に 君との居場所があるように
In the future we both talked about, as if there is a place for us.
Oh baby I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね つないだ手信じて 歩いてゆくと誓うよ
I want to be everything to you and swear to walk together.
逃げないここから 真実をこの手にする
I won't run away from here, to hold the truth in these hands.
笑顔も涙も 自分たちの色で 輝いて
Smiles and tears, shining in our own colors.
2人語った未来に 君との居場所があるように
In the future we talked about, may there be a place with you.
近道なんてないのかな だけど
There's no such thing as a shortcut, but...
楽しいだけならば きっと 幸せ見失う
If it's only fun, we're bound to lose sight of true happiness.
まっすぐ自分の言葉 君に届かないときは
When my honest words don't reach you straight,
不意に無口になるけれど いつかどこかで分かり合える
We grow quiet, but we always understand each other eventually.
悲しみを避けて 笑うのは簡単 諦め上手の 大人になりたくない
Avoiding sadness and smiling is easy, but I don't want to give up.
自分ひとりだけ 空回りしてると 誰もが器用に 生きてる気がする
When I'm spinning my wheels, everyone else seems so skillful.
ひとを傷つけて 自分を守る弱さは 虚しさ残して やがて自分も傷つく
The weakness of hurting others leaves emptiness and hurts us too.
2人歩むスピードは きっと同じはずじゃないからね もしも君となり この手が離れたときは 見失わないように きっとむかえに来てね
The speed we walk won't be the same, so come welcome me if we part.
I can't stop my love for you
2人語った未来に 君との居場所があるように
In the future we both talked about, may there be a place for me.
Oh baby I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね つないだ手信じて 歩いてゆくと誓うよ
I want to be everything to you and swear to walk together.
Oh baby I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね 繋いだ手信じて
I want to be everything to you, believing in our joined hands.
歩いてゆくと誓うよ
I swear to walk together with you.
2人の目の前 謎めきひろがった 未完成な地図
Before our eyes, a mysterious and expanding uncompleted map,
でも とても とても とても 心動いた…
But my heart was moved so, so, so much...
どんな言葉 並べてみても 語りきれない想い
No matter what words I arrange, feelings I cannot fully tell,
この愛が ささやくよ 愛しさの意味を
This love whispers the meaning of tenderness.
I can't stop my love for you
2人歩むスピードは きっと同じはずじゃないからね
The speed at which we walk surely won't be the exact same.
の意味を
...what they mean.
I can't stop my love for you
二人歩むスピードは きっと同じはずじゃないからね
Our walking speeds are bound to differ, right?
もしも君と離れてこの手が離れたときは 見失わないようにきっと迎えに来てね
If we ever get separated, be sure to come meet me.
「大嫌い」なんて ウソでも言わないけど
I can't even say "I hate you" as a joke,
「大好き」だってウソなんかじゃ言わないからね
and I wouldn't say "I love you" as a joke either!
会えない時間さえ君は 何も考える余裕もないくらい
Even when we can't meet, you leave me no time to think about anything else,
この心をひとりじめにするんだからね
making me all about you.
I can't stop my love for you
2つの愛が離れてしまわないように1つに抱いていて
I want to hold both our loves as one so they won't drift apart,
それでも不安な夜は 訪れるものだからね
but uneasy nights are bound to come anyway.
そんなときはギュッと 大げさに抱きしめていて
When that happens, hold me tight and close.
かけがえのないもの 君がたくさんここにくれたけど
You've given me so many irreplaceable things,
何よりも一番 かけがえのないものは 君なんだ
but more than anything, the most irreplaceable thing is you.
I can't stop my love for you
君との居場所があるように
There's a place where you and I belong, so...
I can't stop my love for you
君のすべてになってね
You've become everything to me.
つないだ手信じて 歩いてゆくと誓うよ
I swear to walk on, believing in our linked hands.
2人の目の前 謎めきひろがった 未完成な地図
Before our eyes, an incomplete map unfolds.
でも とても とても とても 心動いた...
Even so, my heart was moved so much...
どんな言葉 並べてみても
No matter what words I put together,
語りきれない想い
I can't express all my feelings.
この愛が ささやくよ 愛しさの意味を
This love whispers the meaning of love.
I can't stop my love for you
潔く カッコ良く 生きてゆこう...
Let's live purely and coolly...
たとえ2人離れ離れになっても...
Even if the two of us end up apart...
Take my revolution
潔く カッコ良く 明日からは
Let's live purely and coolly starting tomorrow,
誰もが振り向く女になる
becoming a woman that everyone turns to look at.
たとえ2人離れ離れになっても 心はずっと一緒に
Even if the two of us end up apart, our hearts will always be together.
Take my revolution
たとえ2人離れ離れになっても 心はずっと一緒に
Even if the two of us end up apart, our hearts will always be together.
Take my revolution
たとえ2人離れ離れになっても 私は世界を変える
Even if the two of us end up apart, I will change the world.
潔く カッコ良く 生きて行こう
Let's live purely and coolly...
(Just a long long time...)
どうしようもないじゃない
There's nothing we can do about it, right?
でもね 私たち ともだちのこと
But you know, we cherish our friends
何より大切にしている きっと大人よりも
more than anything else, surely more than adults do.
夢を見て 涙して 傷付いても
Seeing dreams, shedding tears, even if we get hurt,
現実はがむしゃらに苦しい
reality is recklessly painful,
自分の居場所 存在価値はなくて 自分を守るために
with no place or worth of my own, to protect myself—
潔く カッコ良く 明日からは 誰かが振り向く女になる
Purely and coolly, starting tomorrow, I'll become a woman that everyone turns to look at.
たとえ2人離れ離れになっても 心はずっと一緒に
Even if the two of us become separated, our hearts will always be together.
戻れない それぞれの道を選ぶ時が来る前に
Before the time comes to choose our separate paths of no return,
こんなにも こんなにも大切な思い出 解き放てよ
let's release these precious, precious memories!
Take my revolution 生きてゆこう
Take my revolution, let's live on,
現実はがむしゃらに苦しい
reality is recklessly painful,
自分の居場所 存在価値を見つけたい 今までの自分を
I want to find my place and worth, my self up until now—
一線超えて捨て去る 儚いなる 自分を野生の豹のように
cross the line and discard my fleeting self, like a wild leopard,
たとえどんなに離れ離れになっても 私は世界を変える
even if we become far apart, I will change the world!
いつの日か Destination
Someday, Destination...
辿り着くから
We will reach it.
Go-Round
[Title: Go-Round]
奇跡の風が胸吹き抜ける ちょっと思い切り強くなれる気がして
A miraculous wind blows through my chest, making me feel like I can be a bit stronger,
順調な 毎感情が 騒ぎ出す
and my smooth emotions start to stir!
知らず知らずに鍵をかけていた ラブハートたちは
Unknowingly, I had kept them locked away—my love hearts,
いまクソニュートンの恋の剣を振り解き放て
now uninhibited, unleash Newton's sword of love!
煌めきをバックに詰め込んで 君が笑う其処縁まで行こう
Packing the sparkle into my back, let's go all the way to where you smile—
不思議なパワー ふたりで呼び覚ませ
what a mysterious power, waking it up together!
回れメリーゴーラウンド 揺らめくフューチャー 負けないくらい信じて
Go round, merry-go-round, a swaying future—believe in it enough not to lose,
強く夢見ゴーラウンド 抱きしめたいよ ギュッと日常になる日まで
dream strongly, go round, I want to hold you tight until it becomes everyday life,
回れメリーゴーラウンド 大事なメッセージ 忘れずでいますぐ
go round, merry-go-round, don't forget the important message, right now—
君の胸にゴーラウンド 今伝えたいんだ 愛は無敵だと
into your chest, go round, I want to tell you right now that love is invincible!
ガラスの扉激しく叩いて 未来の自分を写して
Striking the glass door fiercely, reflecting my future self,
迷わずに次のステージへ舞い上がれ
soaring up to the next stage without hesitation!
永遠のアベンジャーを信じて 息を整えて 口づけをしたら
Believing in the eternal avenger, catching my breath, and if we share a kiss,
未来のエナジー 溢れ出してくるよ
energy for the future will overflow!
まわれメリーゴーランド 輝ける未来
Spin, merry-go-round, a shining future
切ないくらい 感じて
Feeling it almost to the point of ache
なぜかふたりぼっち
For some reason, just the two of us
出会えたことを ずっと大切にしたい
I want to always cherish the fact that we met
まわれメリーゴーランド 楽しいストーリー
Spin, merry-go-round, a fun story
感じたまま 進もう 君のためにゴーランド
Let's keep going as we feel it, go-round for your sake
指切りしよう 愛をはなさない
Let's pinky swear, never let go of love
まわれメリーゴーランド めくるめくフューチャー
Spin, merry-go-round, a dazzling future
負けないくらい 信じて
Believe in it so much you won't lose
強く夢にゴーランド 抱きしめたいよ ギュッと虹になる日まで
Go-round strongly into dreams, want to hold you tight until it turns into a rainbow
まわれメリーゴーランド 大切なメッセージ
Spin, merry-go-round, an important message
忘れないで いま歌う 君の胸にゴーランド
I'm singing right now, don't forget it, go-round in your heart
まわれメリーゴーランド 楽しいストーリー
Spin, merry-go-round, a fun story
感じたまま 進もう
Let's keep going as we feel it
君のためにゴーランド 指切りしよう 愛をはなさない
Go-round for your sake, let's pinky swear, never let go of love
君を守るためこの地に
To protect you in this place
君と出会うため生まれた
I was born to meet you
目覚めた瞬間
The moment I awakened
廻りはじめるプリズム
The prism begins to spin
君を愛するために今
Now, to love you
君を抱くため生まれた
I was born to hold you
嘘も真実も
Both lies and truth
全て自分の中にある
Are all inside myself
心置き去りにしている 日々に負けない
I won't lose to the days leaving my heart behind
優しさ 愛しさ もう一度取り戻そう
Let's regain kindness and affection once more
操り人形な 毎日の中で
In days like a puppet
ゼロと無限の 狭間を迷っている
Wandering between zero and infinity
絡まった糸を 断ち切る力は
The power to cut the tangled threads
君の心の 中に まだ眠っている
Is still sleeping deep inside your heart
ぬくもりを感じるために
To feel warmth
涙を忘れず生きてく
I will live without forgetting tears
遠い記憶にも
Even in distant memories
刻まれてるシステム
The system is engraved
微笑み取り戻すために 君と共に歩いていく
To regain smiles, I will walk together with you
愛も裏切りも 同じ数だけ潜んでる
Love and betrayal lurk in equal numbers
人間を信じることに 臆病にならない
I won't be cowardly about believing in people
まっすぐ見つめて 明日を変えていこう
Gazing straight ahead, let's change tomorrow
からくり人形の 瞳のその奥
Deep within the puppet's eyes
仕組まれた夢に 心が揺れてる
My heart trembles at the programmed dream
錆びたネジを 捨て去る勇気は
The courage to cast away the rusted screw...
ぼくの 心で もう 目覚めはじめている
Already awakening deep within my heart...
操り人形な 毎日のなかで
Amidst days like a marionette,
ゼロと無限の 狭間を迷っている
wandering between zero and infinity.
絡まった糸を 断ち切る力は
the power to cut the tangled threads
君の 心の中に まだ眠っている
is still sleeping deep within your heart.
からくり人形の 瞳のその奥
Deep within the eyes of the clockwork doll,
仕組まれた夢に 心が揺れてる
my heart wavers in a rigged dream.
錆びついたネジを 捨て去る勇気は
The courage to throw away the rusted screws
ぼくの 心で もう 目覚めはじめている
is already awakening within my heart.
梅雨明け前の 青空は
The blue sky before the rainy season ends—
人は早く 心を踊らせる
people eagerly make their hearts dance.
今年も もうすぐ 夏が来る
Soon, summer will be here once again.
街も人も 浮かれ気分で 騒めきだす
The town and its people bustle with excitement.
わたしは といえば あなたを想い
As for me, I think of you
この街で 新しい 風に吹かれて
and feel the new breeze blowing through this town.
少しの 不安を 抱きしめながら
While holding close a little bit of anxiety,
叶えたい 明日だけを 見つめている
I keep my eyes fixed solely on the tomorrow I want to fulfill.
少年の 心のまま 大人になったひと
Someone who grew into an adult with a boy's heart—
ふたりで 出会った あの日には 戻れないけど
even though we can never return to the day we met,
瞳を閉じれば 微笑む顔が見える
if I close my eyes, I can see your smiling face.
大好きな あの歌 今も歌ってますか?
Are you still singing that song we loved so much?
私には 聞こえる 優しい声とメロディ
I can hear your gentle voice and melody.
弱気な ときほど あなたを思い出す
Whenever I feel weak, I remember you.
ときおり 自分が 嫌いになるのは
Sometimes, when I grow to dislike myself,
軽はずみな 言葉で 誰かを傷つけ
it's because my careless words hurt someone,
そのくせ 弱くて ちっぽけだから
and yet I am so weak and small.
逃げようと する私を 叱ってください
Please scold me when I try to run away.
ふたりで 歌った メロディ 口ずさんでみれば
When I hum the melody we sang together,
涙が ひとすじ 流れて 会いたくなった
a single tear falls, and I longed to see you.
受話器越しに 聞いて 聞かせてくれた
Listening through the phone receiver, the Dearest
リフレインする デュエット 胸に切なく響く
duet echoes with poignant pain in my chest.
鮮やかすぎる眩暈 迷い悩む未来も
Even in this dazzling vertigo and my hesitating future,
あなたを忘れない
I will never forget you.
少年の心のまま 大人になった人
You became an adult with a boy's heart intact,
二人で会ったあの日には戻れないけど
We can never return to the day we met, but...
瞳を閉じれば ほほ笑む顔が見える
When I close my eyes, I can see your smiling face.
大好きなあの歌 今も歌ってますか
Are you still singing that song you loved so much?
私には聞こえる 優しい声とメロディ
I can hear it—a gentle voice and melody,
弱気な呼吸音と あなたを思い出す
Reminding me of my timid breathing and you.
受話器越しにギター弾いて 聞かせてくれた
You played the guitar over the receiver for me.
フェードインするフレーズ 胸に切なく響く
Fading phrases echoing painfully in my chest.
鮮やかすぎる眩暈 迷い悩む未来も あなたを忘れない
Even in this dazzling vertigo and hesitating future, I'll never forget you.
あなたを忘れない
I'll never forget you.
みんな！ライブ楽しんでますかー！
Everyone! Are you enjoying the live stream?!
ここまでみんなは何曲知ってましたかー？
How many songs did you know up to this point?
初めて聞いた曲もあったかな？
Were there any songs you heard for the first time?
今回尺の都合で歌えない曲もたくさんあって、平成初期のアニソンは名曲もいっぱいで、何を歌おうかすっごく悩みました！
There were so many songs we couldn't sing due to time limits, and early Heisei anime has so many classics, I struggled so much choosing!
まだまだ盛り上がっていきますよー！今回選んだ曲とかコラボ相手についてなんかは、また振り返りとかで、ゆっくりお話しさせてください！
We're going to keep the energy going! Please let me talk more about the songs and collab partners in a recap stream later!
ハッシュタグも活用してしてくれるかな？
I hope you'll use the hashtag too!
えー、そしてすでに気づいている人ももしかしたらいるかもしれないですが、
Um, and some of you might have already realized this, but...
実はここまでの曲、なんとすべてオープニング曲だったんですよ！
Actually, all the songs up to now were opening themes!
ってことは！次からはエンディング曲パートにいっちゃうぞー！
That means! From here on, we're moving on to the ending song part!
冷たっ、え、何々何々？雪？
Cold—wait, what, what? Snow?
靴の底がすり減ってる まるで今のココロみたい…
The soles of my shoes are worn down, just like my heart right now...
他人と深く分かり合うって 難しいと感じたよ
I felt that deeply understanding others is so difficult.
うなずくことしかできない自分 嫌いになってる
I've come to hate myself for only being able to nod along.
世の中には思い通りいかないことあるけれど
In this world, things don't always go the way you want, but
落ち込むだけ落ち込んだら 笑ってまた歩かなきゃ
after sinking into despair, you have to smile and walk again.
だけどゆずれない大切なものは守り通したい
But I want to protect the precious things I cannot yield.
ユメ実現するための犠牲はもう嫌だよ
I'm sick of sacrifices just to make dreams come true!
気持ちに嘘つくようなことはやめて YESのいい子は卒業しよう
Stop lying to your feelings, let's graduate from being a "yes-man" good girl!
そうすればきっと自分のことを好きになれるはずだよ 強気でいこう
If you do that, you should surely learn to love yourself. Let's go strong!
一目惚れで
Falling in love at first sight,
恋におちた かれこれ2年たったけど
it's been two years since then.
ドアを閉めた
Closing the door,
音でわかる
I can tell by the sound—
もう目が覚めたね 私たち
we're both waking up now.
誰かと私の 間を行ったり来たりしてた と
We've been coming and going,
気づいていたけど
even though we knew,
ひとりになるのが 怖かった
being alone was too scary.
魂を売るようなことはやめて
Let's stop lying to ourselves,
都合のいい恋は卒業しよう
and graduate from convenient love!
迷いのある人生だっていいよ
It's okay to have a wandering life,
どんな闇だって
no matter how much darkness there is—
超えてみせる
we'll overcome it!
嫌われたくない想いが 自由の羽根 踏みつけた
We trampled on the wings of freedom,
飛べないまま
unable to fly.
終わりたくない 想いのまま
Even so, I don't want it to end;
想いのまま 生きていたい
I want to live true to my feelings!
気持ちに嘘をつくようなことはやめて
Let's stop lying to our feelings,
YES都合のいい恋は卒業しよう
and graduate from convenient love!
そうすればきっと自分のことを好きになれるはずだよ
If we do, we're bound to love ourselves.
強く生きていこう
Let's keep going strong!
迷いのある人生だっていいよ
It's okay to have a wandering life,
どんな闇だって
no matter how much darkness there is—
超えてみせる
we'll overcome it!
たったひとつしかない自分
With just one precious thing,
好きになろう
let's learn to love ourselves.
would you call me if you need my love ?
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear it everywhere,
君がくれる agape
the agape you gave me.
力の限り dive !
With all my might, dive!
見つめる 触れ合う その時
To see each other, to touch each other,
愛は二人を試している
when this comes to us,
time is now time is now
この世の果てまで
To the end of the world,
would you call me if you need my love ?
would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear it everywhere.
君がくれる agape
The agape you gave me,
力の限り dive !
with all my might, dive!
信じる 応える その瞬間
To believe, to answer, at the moment,
愛が僕らをひとつにする
the love makes us the one.
time is now time is now
どこまでもしりて
keep on living, forever.
would you call me if you need my love ?
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear it everywhere,
君がくれる agape
the agape you gave me.
力の限り dive !
With all my might, dive!
would you call me if you need my love ?
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
I can hear it everywhere,
君がくれる agape
the agape you gave me.
力の限り dive !
With all my might, dive!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
would you call me if you need my love ? どこに いた って 聞こえる
Would you call me if you need my love? Can you hear me wherever you are?
君 が くれる agape 力 の かぎり dive !
The agape you give me, dive with all your might!
おめでとう 笑顔 が ゆれて
Congratulations, as your smile sways,
ゆるやか に 流れる 奏鳴曲 ( ソナタ )
A sonata flows gently.
ふたり とも ずいぶん 大人 に 見える よ
You both look quite grown up.
長い こと 友達 同士 何 回 も ケンカ し てた ね
As long-time friends, we fought so many times.
気 が つけ ば ふたり 思い出 が 重なる
Before we knew it, our memories overlap.
男 とか 女 とか じゃ なく 何 でも 話せる ふたり だった ね
Not as man or woman, but two who could talk about anything.
短い よう で 長い 道 を 旅 し て ふたり ここ に 立ってる
Traveling a short yet long road, here we stand together.
高らか に 鳴り 響く 鐘 の 音 は 晴れやか な 今日 が ゴール じゃ なく て
The clear ringing bell tone isn't because today is the goal,
お 互い の 胸 の 奥 響き あう これ から も 続く 長い 旅 を 告げる 勇気 の 鐘
resonating deep in each other's chests, proclaiming the long journey ahead—the bell of courage.
夢 を みる ふたり いっしょ に
Dreaming together,
ひとり で は たどりつけ ない
We cannot reach it alone.
邪魔 な の は 後悔 と すい プライド
What gets in the way is regret and frail pride.
彼 の 目 に 汗 が にじんで うつむいて 弱音 吐く なら
If tears blur his eyes and he hangs his head, speaking weakly,
その 頬 を 泣いて でも たたいて あげて
Hit that cheek even as you cry, lift him up.
瞬間 だけ の なぐさめ なんて
Momentary comfort
中途半端 な 優しさ に 似 てる
resembles half-hearted kindness.
はるか 彼方 に 昇る 太陽
The sun rising far away—
顔 を あげて なきゃ 瞳 が くもる
if you don't lift your face, your eyes will cloud over.
いつまで も 鐘 の 音 が 響く よう に 深呼吸 で
So that the bell rings forever, with a deep breath...
深呼吸で心に風を送ろう
Take a deep breath and let the wind fill your heart
だけどもしふたりめげたりしたら
But if the two of us ever get discouraged,
一番乗りで待っていてあげたい
I want to be the first to wait for you
勇気の丘
on the Hill of Courage.
なだらかなレンガの階段を 腕をくみふたり登りはじめる
Arm in arm, we start climbing the gentle brick stairs together.
お互いに夢をかかえあえたら
If we can share our dreams with each other,
夢に近づたび クレッシェンドする 勇気の鐘
the Bell of Courage crescendos as we get closer to our dreams.
乾いた風が吹く
A dry wind blows,
街は凍えている
and the city is freezing.
いくつの季節が そっとともなく 過ぎ去ったのだろう
How many seasons have quietly passed us by?
雪降る人はみな
Everyone in the snow
想いに身を包んで
wraps themselves in their thoughts,
遠くに揺れる影の中に 明日を見つける
finding tomorrow within the swaying shadows in the distance.
明日を見つける
Finding tomorrow...
この手をこぼれ落ちる 砂のような感情
Emotions like sand slipping through these hands
あの時 胸に突き刺さった 言葉が無駄に響くけど
Though the words that pierced my chest back then echo in vain,
あの時 胸に刺さった
The words that pierced my chest back then...
言葉が無駄に響くけど
Though words echo in vain,
果てない夜を数えるから
I'll count the endless nights.
自分の欠片を探していた
I was searching for pieces of myself;
失うほどにこの思いが確かになってく
the more I lose, the more certain this feeling becomes.
今ならきっと歩いてゆける どこまでも
Now I'm sure I can keep walking anywhere, no matter how far.
どうしてこの空は こんなに広いのだろう
Why is this sky so vast?
叫んでみても声にならなくて 涙があふれた
Even when I shout, no voice comes out, and tears overflow.
自由に風が吹いて 鳥たちはどこへ行くの
The wind blows freely, where are the birds going?
少しの時間のように 同じ場所に戻れない
Like a brief moment, we cannot return to the same place.
このまま夢をあきらめても 高鳴ることを抑えきれない
Even if we give up on our dreams like this, we cannot suppress our throbbing hearts.
いつからきっと近づきたい
Since when have I surely wanted to get closer
あの雲の高さ
to the height of those clouds?
桜の蕾が
The cherry blossom buds
そっと 膨らむ頃
begin to gently swell,
夢抱き翔ゆく 弥生の美空へ
soaring into the beautiful March sky.
冬の寒さに 堪えながら
Enduring the cold of winter,
旅立つ春を 待ちわびた
we eagerly awaited the spring of departure.
別れが来ることに 眼を伏せ
Lowering our eyes as partings draw near,
想い出を 繰りながら
while tracing our memories,
卒業は終わりじゃない
graduation is not the end—
まだ見ぬ未来 探す為の旅立ちの日
it is the day of departure to seek an unseen future.
寂他の思い 胸に さみざみと...
With lonely feelings lingering in our chests...
君よ いつ日にか 逢いましょう
My friend, let us meet again someday.
はい、今日はみんな来てくれてありがとうございました！
Hi everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
今日のライブはみんなどうだったかな？
How did everyone find today's live?
悲しいことにお別れの時間が来てしまいました。
Unfortunately, the time has come to say goodbye.
最後はみんなに懐かしい気持ちを噛み締めてもらいたいので、最後の曲を歌う前にお知らせさせてください。
Since I want everyone to cherish some nostalgic feelings at the very end, please let me make some announcements before singing the final song.
まずはこちら、お待たせしました！先日シングルを公開した「アトリエ」のMVが公開されます！
First is this, thank you for waiting! The MV for "Atelier," whose single was released recently, is coming out!
アトリエ過激派もこれで大満足だね！思わず考察したくなるようなMVになってるから、たくさん見てね。
Atelier extremists will be super satisfied with this! It's an MV that makes you want to theorize, so be sure to watch it a lot.
次に、今年もあります、不知火フレア活動4周年記念グッズ！なんとついに、出します！
Next, we have this year's Shiranui Flare 4th Anniversary merch! Yes, we're finally releasing them!
不知火フレア1stアルバム「Canvas」！ジャケットはコタチユウ先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
Shiranui Flare's 1st album, "Canvas"! The jacket illustration was newly drawn by Kotachiyuu-sensei!
楽曲は初めてのオリジナル曲「Smile & Go」はじめ、今年までに歌った曲を加えて、なんとあの「スカイソナタ」をオクレさん本人とデュエットした特別ボーナストラックも収録！ソロとはまた違ったスカイソナタを聞いてみませんか？
It includes our very first original song "Smile & Go," songs sung up to this year, and a special bonus track: a duet of "Sky Sonata" with Okure-san himself! Would you like to hear a different "Sky Sonata" from the solo version?
続いて、澄宮やウルハ先生描き下ろしランダムラバーストラップ！
Next up, random rubber straps illustrated by Sumimiya and Uruha-sensei!
今までの衣装に新衣装やアトリエの衣装のとってもキュートなラバーストラップになってます。どの衣装の私もちょうだいしょ？
They are super cute rubber straps featuring past outfits, new outfits, and the Atelier outfit. Aren't I cute in every single outfit?
え、さらに今回のアルバム「Canvas」をイメージしたリュックサック！フロント部分のファスナには羽ばたくエルフレアチャームがついてます。お召し締めすると飛んでるように見えてかわいいね！
Oh, and furthermore, a backpack inspired by the new album "Canvas"! The front zipper features a fluttering Elfure charm. When zipped up, it looks like it's flying, which is super cute!
裏生地は私や君たちのモチーフにした柄も入ってるよ。私とお揃いのカバンでお出かけしない？
The lining features patterns based on me and you guys. Why don't you go out with a bag matching mine?
えっと、さらにさらにこちらも今回のアルバムイラストで私が持ってる本の表紙と同じデザインの手帳型マルチスマホケース！デザインは金の箔押し付きで、本当の本みたいですごくおしゃれだよ！
And what's more, this diary-style multi smartphone case featuring the exact same design as the book I'm holding in the album illustration! It has gold foil stamping, and it looks just like a real book—super stylish!
そして気になる全部セットは、数量限定だけど「直筆メッセージ＆複製サイン入りポストカード」愛を込めて1枚1枚書いて君に届けるからね！
And as for the all-in-one set, it's quantity-limited, but it comes with a postcard with a handwritten message and duplicated autograph! I'll put my heart into writing each one and deliver it to you!
通常版は複製にはなっちゃうんだけど、数量限定とは違うメッセージ、少し長めに返っちゃうかな？
The regular version will be a printed copy, but maybe I'll write a slightly longer message, different from the limited-quantity one?
最後に知らせです。このあとメンバー限定ミニライブ！今回コンセプトの都合上、オリジナル曲を歌っていなかったので、ほんの少しだけオリジナル曲を歌って踊っちゃおうかなって思います。よかったら遊びに来てください！はい、ということでお知らせは以上です。
Lastly, an announcement. Right after this is a member-limited mini-live! Since we didn't sing original songs due to the concept this time, I thought I'd sing and dance to original songs just a little bit. Please come hang out if you'd like! Alright, that's all for the announcements.
改めて4周年とみんな来てくれて今日は本当にありがとうございました！5周年もよろしくお願いします！
Once again, thank you all so much for coming for my 4th anniversary today! Please look forward to my 5th year as well!
はあ、もう終わりかぁ。夏ももう終わっちゃうな。みんなと出会えて本当に本当によかった。ここが私の幸せの場所です。
Phew, is it already over... Summer is soon coming to an end too. I'm truly, truly glad I met everyone. This is my happy place.
ふたりぶんの青空を
The blue sky meant for two...
ふたりぶんの青空を 君は手で囲んだ
You framed a swath of blue sky with your hands
陽の匂いのする草を 僕は手に結んだ
And I tied sun-scented grass in my hands
風を背に今 僕らが走り抜けたよ
With the wind at our backs, we ran right through
あの大空目指していた
Aiming for that wide sky
遠くへ 遠くへ...
Far away, far away...
越えていく遥か夏も 渡る川の流れも
Crossing distant summers, and the flowing river
いつか変わって いつか忘れて 同じ思い守れずいる
Someday changing, someday forgetting, unable to keep the same feelings
あの大空 目指してた
Aiming for that blue sky...
遠くへ...
Far away...
遠くへ 遠くへ...
Far away, far away...
超えてゆくはるか夏も
Crossing over the distant summer,
わたる川の流れも
and the flowing river,
いつしか変わって いつか忘れて
someday changing, someday forgetting,
同じ想い守れずにいる
unable to protect the same feelings.
ふたりぶんの青空に 飛行機雲とばした
In the blue sky for two, we let loose vapor trails
笑ってる子供たちの 手には虫かご あの思い出
The laughing children had bug cages in their hands, holding that memory
越えていく遥か夢も 流る川のほとりを いつもひとりで いつも歩いた 今は違う道を
Crossing distant dreams along the riverbank, walking always alone, now on a different path
遠くなる遥か夏よ 流る川の町で 僕ら遊んだ 僕ら生きてた 今もおぼえてる
Faraway distant summer in the river town, we played and lived, even now I remember
今も燃え...
Still burning...
遠くへ 遠くへ...
Far away, far away...